如果你要做一个密码测试，你可能已经有很多了。
If you're giving a code test,
which probably a lot of you have already.
如果你没有你可能在你职业生涯的某个时候
If you haven't, you probably will
at some point in your career,
你会给我一个密码测试
you're gonna give a code test.
这些都是你想做的事情。
These are things you want to do.
尽可能直接地使问题变得简单。
Make the problem straightforward,
as much as possible.
应该是这里的要求， bam， bam， bam。
It should be here are the requirements,
bam, bam, bam.
是否符合这些要求?
Do they fulfill these requirements?.
如果你花了 20 分钟来解释这个问题，那不是一个好问题。
If it takes you 20 minutes to explain
the problem, it's not a good problem.
[ LAUGH] 请花两分钟来解释您正在尝试执行的操作或
[LAUGH] It should take two minutes to
explain what you're trying to do or
它应该很明显
it should be readily apparent.
给我读一下提示
Have a read me with tips in there.
如果你想用风格指引也行
If you wanna put in style guidelines,
that's fine too.
但让问题直接变得简单，不要使问题复杂化。
But just make the problem straightforward
and don't over complicate it.
我曾经采访过我的宝石
I once, so my gem stories,
I once interviewed for
或申请成为公司前工程师的角色。
or applied for our a role as
a front engineer for a company.
他们给了我一个密码测试，就是这个点像像素点的图像，所以点像素点，
And they gave me a code test, it was,
given this dot pixel image, so dot pixels,
很多人都不知道那是什么，但它是一个由很小的点组成的图像。
a lot of you won't know what that is, but
it's an image made up of tiny little dots.
他们不是在一起，别在推特上 @ 我。
They're not so together,
don't @ me on Twitter.
我知道所有的图像都是由很小的点组成的
I know all images are made
up of tiny little dots.
但这个是由更大的点组成的。
But this is made of larger dots.
这个想法是，你必须分析这个图像，我对此一无所知。
And the idea was, you had to parse this
image, which I know nothing about.
你得解析这个形象然后创造康韦的人生游戏
You had to parse this image and
then create Conway's game of life so
在 1000 次迭代中，它创建了此图像。
that in 1000 iterations
it created this image.
真正的面试问题
Real interview question.
这些是我当时没有的技能。
These are skills that I
did not have at the time.
我不知道如何解析一个影像从不读康韦的游戏
I didn't know how to parse an image, never
read an implementation of Conway's game of
生命，更不用说让它倒退了。
life, let alone getting
it to run backwards.
这不一定是个好的代码测试。
That's not necessarily a good code test.
也许是为了那个公司
Maybe it was for that company.
不是给我的
It wasn't for me.
我都没做过
I just didn't even do it.
没什么不对的
Nothing wrong with that.
如果你有这样的挑战，你会觉得这不是件好事。
And if you get a challenge that
you're like this isn't good.
我不同意
I don't agree with this.
你不必这么做的
You don't have to do it.
你不必在这方面自杀
You don't have to kill yourself on it.
应对所有挑战都是好的。
It's good to take on all challenges.
但如果你觉得这是侮辱
But if you feel like this is insulting or
这和我的技能不相关你不用这么做
this isn't relevant to my skill set,
you don't have to do it.
没事的没事的
It's okay.
然后给他们反馈
And give them that feedback.
如果你可以说，我不觉得我的技能有关系，
If you can say like, I don't feel
it's relevant in my skill set,
很有礼貌但没问题
be polite about it, but that's fine.
但如果你给密码测试我真正想要的人做什么
But if you're giving the code test
what I really want people to do and
这是我们根本不做的事情，要诚实面对时间的限制。
this is something we don't do at all,
be honest with the time constraints.
这是密码测试需要五到七个小时
Here's a code test,
it's gonna take five to seven hours.
我通常会把他们告诉我的东西翻倍
I usually double whatever
they tell me it's gonna take.
如果他们说要花十个小时大概需要 20 个小时
If they say it's gonna take ten hours,
it'll probably take 20 hours.
想想感同身受
And think about empathy.
你想在桌子的另一边找工作吗
Would you wanna be on the other side
of the table, you're looking for a job,
有人像我一样
and someone's like hey,
这是一个密码挑战需要八个小时才能完成
here's a code challenge that's
gonna take eight hours to complete.
那是你在做的八小时无酬劳动
That's eight hours of unpaid
labor that you're doing, and
要花八个小时以上的时间
it's gonna take them
more than eight hours.
所以尽量把它保持在两到三个小时的范围内
So try to keep it down to
the two to three hour range,
你能在这件事上做点什么
something you can complete in that.
如果可能的话，给他们选择。
And if possible, give them the option.
这是我最喜欢的东西之一
This is one of my favorite things.
给他们选择
Give them the option.
给他们说我们有个密码测试要两三个四个小时
Give them say hey we have a code test
gonna take two, three, four hours.
或者我们有个电话屏幕要一个小时
Or we have a phone screen,
it's gonna take an hour.
因为不同的人有不同的长处。
Because different people
have different strengths.
有些人，生活代码想把它弄明白，他们很棒。
Some people, live code wanna get it done,
they're great at that.
有些人，他们会感到焦虑，他们会感到紧张。
Some people, they get anxiety,
they get nervous.
所以在这件案子里给他们一个密码测试
So in that case give them a code test,
给他们一些能坐下来研究的东西想办法
give them something they can sit
down research, figure out how to do.
所以，如果可能的话，给人们一个选择。
So if possible, give people an option.
我想我们都应该这样做
I think we should all be doing that
因为有时我很着急
as engineers because
sometimes I'm in a hurry.
我想让我们把这事弄明白
I'm like, let's just get this done.
把电话给我
Give me the phone screen.
有时我有时间这对我来说很重要
Sometimes I got time and
this is really important to me.
我要给你看看我能做什么
I'm going to show you what I can do.
我去做密码测试
I'll do the code tests.
重要的是，有代码复审核对表。
Importantly, have a code review checklist.
应该沿着这条线看
It should look something
along these lines.
所以，你可以向所有人申请一个 rubric 。
So as in have a rubric that
you can apply to everybody.
所以在这样做的过程中，你消除了任何偏见，比如，嘿，这个人叫杰姆
So in doing this, you remove any bias you
have, like, hey, this person's named Jem
所以我打赌他们会在这个密码测试中做得很好
too, so I bet they're gonna do
pretty well at this code test.
我已经有偏见了
I already have bias there.
有一个 rubric ，你可以给所有正在审查的工程师
Having a rubric that you can give
to all engineers who are reviewing
这个代码测试意味着它不止一个可以复审测试的人员。
this code test means it's more than
one person that can review the tests.
这不仅仅是一个工程师，你可以公平地向每个人申请。
It's not just one engineer and
you can apply it fairly to everybody.
他们是例外我们想马上把他们带到现场
They're exceptional, we wanna bring them
on site immediately and if they pass,
我们会给他们很高的工资他们做得很好
we're gonna give them very high salaries,
they did really well.
那是什么让他们特别的
Well what makes them exceptional?
你认为自己是一个杰出的工程师是什么呢 ?
What are things you consider
to be an exceptional engineer?
如果他们是普通的那也很好
Well if they're average, that's fine too.
你是在找普通工程师吗
Are you looking for average engineers?
是啊也许吧
Yeah, maybe.
或者你就像我只想要顶级的，例外的或是破产的
Or maybe you're like I only want top tier,
exceptional or bust.
那是你的
That's on you.
我不想告诉你具体怎么聘用
I'm not gonna tell you how
to hire specifically, but
我可以告诉你面试的方式
I can tell you how to the interview.
但是做这些事情是大公司的事了
But doing stuff like this is again
things that larger companies have down,
每个公司都有这样做的地方
they've got every company for
something like this where they should.
开始吧是个小混混
Start ups, it's a little mixed bag.
这就是我之前得到的一点因为如果我说的是 ES2019
And this is a point that has gotten me
before because if I use a say ES2019 or
在我的剧本里我和那个人都不明白
a ES2020 in my scripts and
the person doesn't understand that,
这可能不是什么 JavaScripts ，失败。
there might be like,
this isn't JavaScripts, fail.
但如果你有这种粗鲁的感觉我真的不明白
But if you have this rubric of like,
hey, I don't really get this, but
他们使用先进的功能
they use advanced features.
这也太酷了把它放好
That's cool too, put that under good.
是啊但你只想要一个公平的竞争环境
Yeah, but you just want a level
playing field, you wanna make it
当你给某人一个密码测试时是可以预测的
as predictable as possible when
you give someone a code test.